Risk everything, trust no one
Firebird is a drama, romance, war film directed by Peeter Rebane.
At the height of the Cold War, a troubled soldier forms a forbidden love triangle with a daring fighter
pilot and his female comrade amid the dangerous surroundings of a Soviet Air Force Base.
Sergey, played by Tom Prior.
Roman, played by Oleg Zagorodnii.
Luisa, played by Diana Pozharskaya.
Volodja, played by Jake Henderson.
Major Zverev, played by Margus Prangel.
Polkovnik Kuznetsov, played by Nicholas Woodeson.
Firebird is a 2021 romantic war drama film directed, co-written, and co-produced by Peeter Rebane (in
his feature directorial debut), based on Sergey Fetisov's memoir The Story of Roman.
The film stars Tom Prior (who also co-wrote and
co-produced), Oleg Zagorodnii, and Diana Pozharskaya.
Set in the Soviet Air Force during the Cold War, it tells the true story
of forbidden love between a private and a fighter pilot.
Firebird had its world premiere at the 35th BFI Flare:
London LGBTIQ+ Film Festival on 17 March 2021.
The film also screened at the 45th Frameline: San Francisco International LGBTQ+ Film
Festival on 27 June 2021, where it won an honorable mention for Best First Feature.
The film had a limited theatrical release in the United
States by Roadside Attractions on 29 April 2022.
The film explores themes of cold war, 1970s, lgbt,
lgbt in the military, gay theme.
The tone is emotional.